One of our top comments was that basically there was
no comment in this but the calls that came continuously from
many customers were saying that
RTI what, it is
also our topic by doing RTI and it was
also covered in short under the Aadhar plan, so the customer was
saying that under RTI does the insurance
company give the full invoice value, so
today I have brought it as proof,
I have brought it with the proof, okay now let's
talk, see what has been brought in the assessment, the
insurance company
makes an assessment when the vehicle incurs major losses or
on every loss the insurance company
makes an assessment, but in major losses especially the
assessment is sometimes shared
with us, so today I am sharing it with you, I am
explaining it, okay, so
this is the assessment of Alto 800 car,
which car is it, Alto
800, when is the car, it is a 2020 car, it is a
2 year old car, okay and the ID also,
if seen then its ID is also 230, so
in the policy which  The ID mentioned is also 2
lakh 37000 but in this RTI is obligated, the
customer has taken it under the RTI Aadhar plan,
okay, so earlier also I had
told that RTI means that in the vehicle that
you buy, from registration to the
insurance of on-damage, till that point the
insurance
company scraps the insurance, that means the on-road price of the vehicle will be given to
you after subtracting the compulsory third party insurance,
okay, because till the time the
vehicle is not running on the road, there is compulsory
third party insurance, okay, that will be
subtracted, there is
ID also, so why did the matter of RTI come up, it comes up only when the
vehicle is total loss or stolen, so it is
obvious that
brother, there will be more damage in it, the list of parts will be
more, still how have the
parts been serialized, I will
tell you once in short, okay, it is
of 200760, in this way you must be checking the sensor temperature of
920, the sensor oxygen is of
2770, I will go in short,
go to number 14, the motor is of 2925  Wiper with
bracket is fine and let's move ahead, in this
way the insurance company makes a loss assessment of
your damaged vehicle, that
how much will it cost to repair it, okay, the
value of the damaged parts has been marked and the
cost of labor for repairing it is, see the parts
total parts which is
144239 174239, here the total parts have to be fitted,
a vehicle which has been damaged,
I have told some parts, see go to the last 122,
wheel component means what does it have to be, two
pieces, its rim will also be fitted, this much damage is there,
axle rear
2575, its rear axle has to be changed, it is
worth this much, if we add the total 124 items then it
becomes 174239, okay, in this the labor
and painting charges for repairing it, you must be
seeing how much is required for full body painting,
okay, after that cutting, welding,
fitting, whatever, if we look at all these things then it was
54000 without tax and the tax increased
₹9720 added to 600 sorry
63720 is how much the
insurance company is spending on labour to make this vehicle,
so the total insurance
company added the parts and labour,
so
after adding the parts and labour, another 1500 was
given to him, for what the vehicle was brought by crane, that is why
1500 maximum is given,
okay, for bringing the vehicle by crane,
and if the vehicle is below 1500 cc, then
₹1000 was deducted from it and salvaged, okay, the
parts of the vehicle which will be changed will have some
salvaged value, that was considered 8469,
okay, and that was mined, so
finally ₹239000, which was this much after adding the spare parts,
less compulsory
deductible and the
salvaged value, both were mined,
so
how much is the value of the vehicle, 2 37 I had
written the idea of ​​the vehicle above, then I will
write it here, the ID is also there
[Music]
237000 26000 rupees okay
so how much is this assessment, means the
insurance company is spending 2 lakh
30000 in making this car
now if RTI has not been taken then the
insurance company is spending 2
lakh 30000 in making it but
in case of not taking RTI it will be 2 lakh 37000 because there is
also an ID which the customers understand, that is if there is
any kind of damage to the car, if the car is stolen
or is in a condition to be repaired then an ID is
also given, everyone knows that okay
so the insurance company is understanding the expense of 230
in making the car now
what will the insurance company do brother,
he has to pay 6000 from home but the car also becomes
his, right what will happen to the customer of the insurance company
1000 from here the
value of 236 will be reduced by 1000
how much will it be in 237 sorry 1000 will be reduced
in 236 we are talking about that
time okay
he will get the car  You will not be able to get it by selling it, even
if you sell it at the rate of per kg, you will
easily get around 20000 rupees, understood?
110000 has been considered by the insurance company,
sorry yes, let
me clarify this, when
we are in a situation where the vehicle is not repaired
and the insurance company sells the damaged vehicle, then it
sells it in two ways, one by
cancelling the RC and the other by cancelling the RC,
okay, when the RC is cancelled then it is
sold at the price of scrap and if it is
sold not by cancelling the RC but with the RC, then
they buy some salvenger, make it,
transfer the name and go, so
when the RC is sold without cancellation then the
value of the vehicle will be good, okay, and
if you sell it after cancelling the RC then it will be
less, an
injection of 40000
and it is with 110000,
so you must be understanding, there is an expense of 230 rupees,
okay and if you sell the vehicle after
cancelling the RC then you will get approximately 40000, so
understand  How much will the insurance company pay to the customer from home,
one 96 one 96 plus the
company benefits from not making the vehicle
and if it is saved without cancelling the RC then the
insurance company is getting Rs. 110000
in the market
so there is double profit there too now
how is this non RTI
75% of ID also the expense in ID
which is the liability of the insurance company is
more than 75% when it goes more than 75%
then it comes in the category of total loss
so did
I tell what is the benefit in RTI
but because RTI act has been done
so invoice value has to be given in this vehicle
with time after two years the domestic value of the watch may
become 236 or 237 okay
but RTI has been taken so it has to
get invoice value see
so the price of the vehicle was 37053 and on damage
premium became
9179 okay and plus road tax has been
paid, the vehicle has not been driven for 15 years so let's
zoom a little
it becomes
337879 this means  The final invoice value has been reached,
even if the ID of this vehicle is 2 lakh 37000 in the policy,
but RTI has been taken,
due to this if there is a total loss then 3 lakh
37 will have to be paid to the insurance company,
understood? Now what will the insurance company do in the total loss, it will now compare it with the
invoice value, it will
not do it with IDBI, understood? You have
68% of invoice protect
cover, now if it crosses 75% then on totaling it is
68%,
okay, now it is written in it that the vehicle is
not repaired, after opening the vehicle some damage may
come out
10%, after this the
expert survey of the insurance company says that 10%
can also increase in it, when the vehicle is dismantled
then it will increase by 10%, then how much will it become
78 and then 78 has been discussed, then
understand that the criteria for total loss has been set in which
case, in the case of RTI also,
understood that
in the RTI case also the vehicle is going into total loss, the
invoice value is 37000 and  The salvaged man has
taken how much, 40000 for the vehicle and 10000,
so after subtracting both of these, it comes to 296879 with
RC cancellation. This is the
liability of the insurance company.
Take the vehicle and sell it as salvage. After paying 296869, the
insurance
company will have to pay
how much the repair cost was. Keep in mind that the
repair cost was
230,
but here if the total loss is being shown as
296,
why? Because RTI has been taken, that's why,
okay, so now if we
evaluate once without cancelling the RC, it is
seen here that brother,
even without cancelling the RC, the wire has put a rate of
110000, the RC will be correct and the vehicle will also be given to the
salvager. Who will be called a salvager? The
vehicle which is not repaired in insurance, they take it away. The
deep salvage which they
make by mixing different parts with their ideas and techniques, okay, then the
insurance company is getting 110000 from there.
1000 will be deducted from the salvage amount,
then how much is the policy expense, the
insurance company will have to
pay 26000,
okay, how much is the cost of one boy in these suits,
2 lakh 30000, so on this condition the
car is totaled, the person will get
3 lakh
37879 because the value
of the car as per the invoice is this, did you understand
my point, yes,
1000 will be deducted from 37879, the compulsory
detective will
finally get
336869, the final amount that will be received will be
336869,
this is the final amount
of the car,
I had told you, but how did the customer get one lakh more,
because RTI
was opted, so this is basically the value of RTI
and ITI is the role of RTI, if we
say RTI, then again return the invoice, many
insurance companies write invoice cover,
many insurance companies write return the invoice, it is
from both,
so please check this two or three times, there is a
little calculator and  Analysis
is a thing and I know that our video is
not for all the people who have cars, only those
boys who want to understand and learn automobile will be able to
understand it
and not everyone will be able to understand it, thank you.